<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carles Hernandez-Ferrer</title>
    <link>http://212.71.254.23/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carles Hernandez-Ferrer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:09:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://212.71.254.23/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Canción de invierno: El tronco de ceniza</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/cancion-invierno-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:09:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/cancion-invierno-21/</guid>
      <description>Después de darle muchas vueltas, me he lanzada a intentar publicar de forma seria algunas de las aventuras que escribo y que dirijo. &amp;ldquo;El tronco de ceniza&amp;rdquo; es la primera. Con una ambientación invernal, la aventura presenta la canción catalana para la familiar celebración de &amp;ldquo;la cagada del tió&amp;rdquo;. He usado esta tradición catalana como semilla para este one-shot navideño.
Aquí el resumen de la aventura:
 Durante los días de más profundo invierno, las familias de Winterbreak se reúnen para celebrar la llegada del nuevo año.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Jordi 2021 (Barcelona &#43; Pandemic II Ed.)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2021/</guid>
      <description>Once again I am coding a digital rose to offer to my wife. This time I&amp;rsquo;m bringing some changes since it is not a &amp;ldquo;static one&amp;rdquo; 😉.
If you press on the following picture you&amp;rsquo;ll be moved to itch.io so you can play this super-minigame where you have to find the 5 hidden roses in the garden.
 St. Jordi 2021: can you find the 5 hidden roses?
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 22:01:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/academic/</guid>
      <description>Section Description     Articles List of publiched, acepted, submitted and scientific articles in preparation.   Talks (Scientific-) Talks I gave during the last years.   Poster (Scientific-) Posters I presented or I participated in the presented research.   Teaching Summary of my experience in teaching.     Articles ♠ : This symbol denotes that the authors consider that the two first authors should be regarded as “joint first authors”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 21:59:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/about/</guid>
      <description>Trajectory I am a researcher at the Data Analysis Team at the Centre Nacional d’Anàlisi Genòmica (CNAG-CRG). I mainly work as a data and software engineer developing new software and improving our existing pipelines for genomic and genomic-related data analyses. I am also a collaborator directing master thesis from the MSc. in Bioinformatics &amp;amp; Biostatitics at the Universitat Oberta de Catalunya.
 Welcome to CNAG-CRG
  Before working at the Centre Nacional d’Anàlisi Genòmica, my research interests included the study of the relations between environmental factors and internal omic perturbations and development of applications to integrate multiple layers of molecular data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2020 - 2021</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 15:10:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>This past year has been a really significant one with many challenges. Therefore I wanted to make a winter card that shows the opposite: simplicity, elegance, and joy.
 Winter card 2020 - 2021: Happy Yultide!
  So, the winter card it is juts a snowing page that allows you to discover your present, from a possible random set of 35 different drawings.
You can play it clicking the previous picture and the code of this card here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rolvember20 día 29: legal</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 02:08:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-29/</guid>
      <description>Esta es la cuarta y última entrada para el #rolvember20. Para cerrar este pequeño capítulo rolero vamos a terminar tal y cómo empezamos, con una semilla de aventura. El concepto, o palabra clave, es &amp;ldquo;legal&amp;rdquo;.
 Adventurer Caravan by Adventurer Caravan (ArtStation)
   En el Ducado de Teeralshi uno no puede entrar sin que haya sido invitado a hacerlo. Esta ley, ideada por el padre del actual duque, fue impuesta para controlar la entrada de extranjeros al ducado a y La Ciudad Roja, centro del ducado y hogar de la Mansión de las Cien Ventanas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rolvember20 día 22: aire</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 12:06:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-22/</guid>
      <description>Para esta tercera entrega para #rolvember20 me propuse escribir una subclase de D&amp;amp;D 5e. Me decidí por el monje, pues es la clase que más desconozco.
Originalmente quería escribir La Senda del Viento pero al dar algo de trasfondo y justificación a esta subclase no pude evitar dar forma y color a La Senda del Hielo también.
La Senda del Viento y La Senda del Hielo en PDF
He usado GM Binder para escribir el documento que contiene ambas subclases, al igual que en las dos anteriores entradas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rolvember20 día 15: limpieza</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:34:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-15/</guid>
      <description>Para la tercera entrega de este #rolvember20 he preparado algo que todo mago o maga, brujo o bruja, conjurador o conjuradora, hechicero o hechicera han echado en falta en algún u otro momento. Se trata, sin más ni menos, que el &amp;ldquo;Kit de limpieza para el mago atareado&amp;rdquo;.
En el documento se encuentra la descripción de cada uno de los nueve objetos creados para completar las tres versión del kit (básica, avanzada y suprema), así como los minoristas aprobados para su venta y distribución en el multiverso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rolvember20 día 8: fuego</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:17:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-8/</guid>
      <description>Esta es la segunda de las entregas a las que me comprometí para #rolvember20. Me propuse el diseño de un nuevo NPC parq ue pudiera ser usado a modo de enemigo de los PJs, aunque en realidad los PJs podría formar parte de &amp;ldquo;El Culto del Fuego Carmesí&amp;rdquo;.
Lo que he hecho a sido diseñar tres perfiles de enemigos. Los tres son de tipo humanoide y son integrantes de una secta de fanáticos llamado &amp;ldquo;El Culto del Fuego Carmesí&amp;rdquo; que fue expulsada de su tierra natal por ser extremista y violenta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rolvember20 día 1: cosecha</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:14:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/rolvember20-1/</guid>
      <description>Este año voy a tomarme en serio participar con (cierta) regularidad a la iniciativa de Manuel Garrido llamada #rolvember20.
Aquí el tuit inaugural:
Aquí está la información y palabras del #rolvember20. Recordad que empieza el 1 de Noviembre. Leed bien las dos imágenes e id preparándoos ;)
Rolvember 2020. Por @GarriManu, con la (maravillosa) colaboración de @Moguchaser y @LaTabernaRolera pic.twitter.com/XX0D9hCGcD
&amp;mdash; 👻Manuel Garrido💀 (@GarriManu) 27 de octubre de 2020 Mi intención es subir un mínimo de una entrada por semana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Jordi 2020 (Barcelona &#43; Pandemic Ed.)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2020/</guid>
      <description>As I did last year (fun-post here), I come again with a digital rose for my wife. This time, a pure-CSS rose.
.container2 {height: 100px;width: 100px;position: relative;top: 60px;bottom: 60px;left: 0;right: 0;margin: auto;}.caption2 {height: 100px;width: 500px;position: relative;top: 125px;bottom: 0;left: 0;right: 0;margin: auto;font-family: &#39;Sacramento&#39;, serif;font-size: 48px;}.subcaption2 {height: 100px;width: 500px;position: relative;top: 100px;bottom: 50px;left: 45%;right: 0;margin: auto;font-family: &#39;Sacramento&#39;, serif;font-size: 23px;}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedural generation of triangular glyphs</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/procedural-generation-of-triangular-glyphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/procedural-generation-of-triangular-glyphs/</guid>
      <description>Some triangular glyphs
  Some days ago I randomly ended into the subreddit on Procedural generation, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t suspect existed. In specific, I ended up into the monthly challange of March 2017.
As you can see there, the challenge was on generating a set of runes, glyphs, or symbols. I found the challenge very interesting and starting from one of the pictures they reference (this one) I decided to create my own generator as an excuse to learn a bit of Haxe and OpenFL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2019 - 2020</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2019-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 15:17:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2019-2020/</guid>
      <description>For this Christmas, I wanted to move the level of the geek christmas card further that I did before.
The previous gamified GCCs were based on a couple of smartphone games. For instance, the one for 2018-2019 was based on a game called Tomb of the Mask and the first on I gamified, 2016-2017, was based on FlappyBird.
This time I wanted to come back in time and bring back an old point-and-click game-system that I played in Where in the world is Carmen Sandiego?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some &#39;must&#39; methods for JavaScript array</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/must-javascript-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/must-javascript-array/</guid>
      <description>I recently been working a lot with JavaScript and I missed some methods for the JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s array.
First I missed three core methods related of the content of the array. A method to get the unique elements in the array (arr.unique()), a method that returns the number of occurrences of a given element (arr.count(val)), and a method that returns some sort of table with the number of occurrences of each unique element in the array - see this one as a combination of the previous two - (arr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code for Care (Hackathon)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/code-4-care-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/code-4-care-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday, June 1st 2019, I attended the hackathon Code for Care organized by Humana Experience Center, at the District Hall (Boston, MA).
The goal of that hackathon was to build a digital software to help [not-necessary] elderly to manage their medications, taking special attention to those individuals with comorbidities (the simultaneous presence of two chronic diseases or conditions in the same individual).
There was no limitation in type of software nor in technology we could use for the development, although we were encouraged to use the FDA’s free drug data API, that provides access to data like adverse events, product labeling, and a full directory of all NDCs (National Drug Codes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Jordi 2019 (Bostod Ed.)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/book-and-rose-2019/</guid>
      <description>Saint Gorge is the patron of Catalonia (a northeast region in Spain). It is the national day of the region and it is celebrated by offering books and roses to your intimate and loved ones (more information about it on this page from Barcelona&amp;rsquo;s City council).
This is the first year outside Catalonia for this day. So, I made this super simple drawing in HTML5 and javacript for my wife, to celebrate this amazing Catalan festivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2018 - 2019</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2018-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 15:17:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2018-2019/</guid>
      <description>Following the tradition, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the geek christmas card for this year. As it is being the trend lately, it is coded in javascript and HTML5.
 Winter card 2018 - 2019: Mike has lost his presents for Santaclaus!
  The card is, again, a minigame where Mike &amp;lsquo;the elf&amp;rsquo; has lost the present he crafter for this Christmas and we need to help him to find them all. Make a click on the picture to play the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting XML data from Human Metabolome Data Base</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/hmdb-xml-to-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/hmdb-xml-to-csv/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on a project where I need to annotate exogenous chemicals measured in plasma using GC-MS/MS to the Human Metabolome Data Base (HMDB) and to the Toxin and Toxin Target Database (T3DB).
T3DB offers a series of downloadable resources that can be easy integrated into R as a CSV file after being parsed using bash. On the other hand, HMDB only offers XML sources that are to heavy to be parsed using the XML R package in my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating KEGG compounds to pathway</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/annotating-kegg-compounds-to-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/annotating-kegg-compounds-to-pathway/</guid>
      <description>To annotate a list of KEGG compounds to the KEGG pathways where they are involved I used the R package KEGGREST from Bioconductor.
library(KEGGREST) So, having a list of KEGG compounds saved in a character vector like kegg_compounds, we use the method keggGet in batches of maximum 10 compounds to annotate them.
The following (rudimentary) code, queries the database in batches of ten compounds fiddling a list (pathways) where it creates an entry per pathway and updates the field compounds with the compounds from kegg_compounds for each pathway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2017 - 2018</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:19:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is the time to follow the tradition of creating a geek christmas card. As I did last year, the one for this year I typed it in javascript. It is much simpler compared to the game of the 2016 Christmas, but I enjoyed coding it.
No picture this time, only the link to it: Merry Christmas 2017-2018.
The card is an HTML5 canvas used as a grid where different pixelled cartoons appear being drawn pixel-a-pixel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring public NHANES data using Rcupcake</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/exploring-public-nhanes-data-using-rcupcake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/exploring-public-nhanes-data-using-rcupcake/</guid>
      <description>The Rcupcake package contains functions to query different databases through the BD2K RESTful API. BD2K RESTful API is an interface that provides access to different data sources, making easier data accessibility, analysis reproducibility and scalability.
The package is installed via devtools using it&amp;rsquo;s GitHub URL (hms-dbmi/Rcupcake) or following their guide (also in GiHub - here).
library( Rcupcake ) library( knitr ) library( stringr ) opts_chunk$set( fig.path=&amp;#39;Figs/&amp;#39;, echo=TRUE, warning=FALSE, message=FALSE, cache=FALSE ) Rcupcake package follows a four-step process to retrieve the data from a database:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-referencing between different files with LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/cross-referencing-between-different-files-with-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/cross-referencing-between-different-files-with-latex/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I want to refer labels I placed in external .tex files. I mean, I want o refer (using the command \ref) a \label from a .tex file I created in another project.
A valid solution it to use the command \include. But I in this case I don&amp;rsquo;t want to include the .tex, I only want to be able to refer their labels.
This can be done using the xr package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change the title of Table of Contents (ToC) in LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/change-the-title-of-table-of-contents-toc-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/change-the-title-of-table-of-contents-toc-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>The steps to change the title of the table of contents (ToC) depends on if you are using the babel package or not.
Without babel The title of the table of contents can be changed using the command \contentsname. Let&amp;rsquo;s see a small example:
\documentclass{article}\renewcommand{\contentsname}{Index} % ToC will show &amp;quot;Index&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;Content&amp;quot;\begin{document}\tableofcontents\section{Section}\subsection{Subsection}\end{document}With babel When using babel package the name of the table of contents needs to be changed for the particular language used with babel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spell-checking in Sublime Text 3</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/spell-checking-and-dictionaries-in-sublime-text-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/spell-checking-and-dictionaries-in-sublime-text-3/</guid>
      <description>I was a fan of the package Dictionaries but is seems that it is no available and that will not be re-included. The package&amp;rsquo;s page in package control is here, indicating that the package was removed.
Anyway, the package is in GitHub and it can be installed from the repository. The steps follows:
 Download the package as a ZIP file Open a terminal on your Downloads folder Unzip the file with unzip Dictionaries-master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2016 - 2017</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2016-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 16:09:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2016-2017/</guid>
      <description>Following the tradition of the last years, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a _geek christmas card:. This year I typed it in javascript using the improvements of HTML5.
 Winter card 2016 - 2017: Mr Snowman has lost his hat!
  The card is a minigame where a small and blue snowman has lost his hat and you need to help him to recover it. The characteristic of the game is that the snowman moves autonomously once the user gave him a direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change key for toggle comment in Sublime Text 3</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/change-key-for-toggle-comment-in-sublime-text-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/change-key-for-toggle-comment-in-sublime-text-3/</guid>
      <description>I love Sublime Text 3 but I&amp;rsquo;m sued to Ctrl + Shift + C to toggle comment the current line or block of lines. The default behaviour of Sublime Text for commenting is:
{ &amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;ctrl+/&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;toggle_comment&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;args&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;block&amp;quot;: false } }{ &amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;ctrl+shift+/&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;toggle_comment&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;args&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;block&amp;quot;: true } }I like it to behave like this:
{ &amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;ctrl+shift+c&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;toggle_comment&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;args&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;block&amp;quot;: false } }So, this lines means that the comments are done by line (not by block) and with the Ctrl + Shift + C key-binding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2015 - 2016</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2015-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 16:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2015-2016/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for the geek christmas card. This year I wrote it in JAVA, and it can generate, randomly, one of four different outputs.
It is the simplest card I coded but I made it thinking in simplicity.
 Winter card 2015 - 2014: ASCI art
  The source code for that can be found at my christmas-card&amp;rsquo;s github (link), inside the folder mc201516. If you take care, you will find a two-output version of this card coded in R 😁.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene-Enrichment in PsyGeNET&#39;s Main-Psychiatric-Disorders</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/gene-enrichment-in-psygenet-s-main-psychiatric-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/gene-enrichment-in-psygenet-s-main-psychiatric-disorders/</guid>
      <description>PsyGeNET is a database that integrates information on psychiatric disorders and their genes (check its About page for more information). The current version of the database centered the information of three main psychiatric disorders: Alcoholism, Depression and Cocaine-Related-Disorders.
Currently the author of PsyGeNET, Alba Gutiérrez, and me are developing an R package (PsyGeNET2R) to query the information stored into the database and to perform some analysis using this information. We thought that could be a good idea to perform an enrichment analysis on the three main psychiatric disorders given a list of genes of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2014 - 2015</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2014-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 22:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2014-2015/</guid>
      <description>Like the previous years, I continued with the tradition of sending a geek christmas card to my workmates.
This year I wrote it in R since it is one of the most used languages at my workplace, CREAL.
 Winter card 2014 - 2015: snowflake recursion!
  The result of running the script I sent (just a source code that loaded a file on the cloud) is seen above. The source code for that can be found at my christmas-card&amp;rsquo;s github (link) as mc201415.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2013 - 2014</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2013_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 22:14:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2013_2014/</guid>
      <description>This year I decided to continue with the tradition I started last year and sending a Christmas Card to my workmates written in python.
The result of running the script I sent is seen below.
 Winter card 2013 - 2014: santa claus is coming to town
  You can see the gallery of cards here and you have the source code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2012 - 2013</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2012-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 22:18:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2012-2013/</guid>
      <description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to send a Christmas&#39; card to my classmates. And since we are a bunch a little geeks, and I&amp;rsquo;m not an exception, here you have the postcard I sent them: A source-code-postcard in python.
The result of running the script is this:
 Winter card 2012 - 2013: snowflake
  You can see the gallery of cards here and you have the source code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Compiler in .Net  (4 of 4)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-4-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-4-of-4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of 4. Here you have the links to each one:
 Building a Compiler in .Net (1 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (2 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (3 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (4 of 4)   Introduction In this forth post I am going to expose some utilities I have implemented for my version of VSLcompiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Compiler in .Net  (3 of 4)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-3-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-3-of-4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of 4. Here you have the links to each one:
 Building a Compiler in .Net (1 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (2 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (3 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (4 of 4)   Introduction In previous posts In this third post we will finish our compiler. In the last part ( number 4 ) we will talk about some educative improvements I&amp;rsquo;ve done to our compiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Compiler in .Net  (2 of 4)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-2-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-2-of-4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of 4. Here you have the links to each one:
 Building a Compiler in .Net (1 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (2 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (3 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (4 of 4)   Introduction In this second post we will implement the two first steps of a compiler: Scanner and Parser. Remember from part 1 a Scanner, also known as Lexical analyser, reads the characters from source code file and compose tokens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Compiler in .Net  (1 of 4)</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-1-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/blog/building-a-compiler-in-net-1-of-4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of 4. Here you have the links to each one:
 Building a Compiler in .Net (1 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (2 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (3 of 4) Building a Compiler in .Net (4 of 4)   Introduction A compiler is a translator. As a translator can translate a piece of text, written in French, to German; a compiler translates a file written in a high level programming language to a low level programming language (like MicroJava or assembly).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
