<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>geek winter card on Carles Hernandez-Ferrer</title>
    <link>http://212.71.254.23/tags/geek-winter-card/</link>
    <description>Recent content in geek winter card on Carles Hernandez-Ferrer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:10:01 +4900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://212.71.254.23/tags/geek-winter-card/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2021 - 2022</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2021-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 10:10:01 +4900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2021-2022/</guid>
      <description>Again, this year has been challanging and we all have been busy coping with all the difulties that the pandeic rasied in our everyday. So, makeing a diference with the last year, this one I created a new small game where you help Noelle collect the presents for her workmakes, scattered accross the office by her clumsy boss.
Winter card 2021 - 2022: Happy Yultide!
You can play it clicking the previous picture and find the code of this card here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2020 - 2021</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2020-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 15:10:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2020-2021/</guid>
      <description>This past year has been a really significant one with many challenges. Therefore I wanted to make a winter card that shows the opposite: simplicity, elegance, and, specially, joy.
Winter card 2020 - 2021: Happy Yultide!
So, the winter card it is juts a snowing page that allows you to discover your present, from a possible random set of 35 different drawings.
You can play it clicking the previous picture. You can find the code of this card here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2019 - 2020</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2019-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 15:17:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2019-2020/</guid>
      <description>For this Christmas, I wanted to move the level of the geek christmas card further that I did before.
The previous gamified GCCs were based on a couple of smartphone games. For instance, the one for 2018-2019 was based on a game called Tomb of the Mask and the first on I gamified, 2016-2017, was based on FlappyBird.
This time I wanted to come back in time and bring back an old point-and-click game-system that I played in Where in the world is Carmen Sandiego?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2018 - 2019</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2018-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 15:17:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2018-2019/</guid>
      <description>Following the tradition, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the geek christmas card for this year. As it is being the trend lately, it is coded in javascript and HTML5.
Winter card 2018 - 2019: Mike has lost his presents for Santaclaus!
The card is, again, a minigame where Mike &amp;rsquo;the elf&amp;rsquo; has lost the present he crafter for this Christmas and we need to help him to find them all. Make a click on the picture to play the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2017 - 2018</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 15:19:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>It is the time to follow the tradition of creating a geek christmas card. As I did last year, the one for this year I typed it in javascript. It is much simpler compared to the game of the 2016 Christmas, but I enjoyed coding it.
No picture this time, only the link to it: Merry Christmas 2017-2018.
The card is an HTML5 canvas used as a grid where different pixelled cartoons appear being drawn pixel-a-pixel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2016 - 2017</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2016-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 16:09:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2016-2017/</guid>
      <description>Following the tradition of the last years, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a _geek christmas card:. This year I typed it in javascript using the improvements of HTML5.
Winter card 2016 - 2017: Mr Snowman has lost his hat!
The card is a minigame where a small and blue snowman has lost his hat and you need to help him to recover it. The characteristic of the game is that the snowman moves autonomously once the user gave him a direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2015 - 2016</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2015-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 16:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2015-2016/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for the geek christmas card. This year I wrote it in JAVA, and it can generate, randomly, one of four different outputs.
It is the simplest card I coded but I made it thinking in simplicity.
Winter card 2015 - 2014: ASCI art
The source code for that can be found at my christmas-card&amp;rsquo;s github (link), inside the folder mc201516. If you take care, you will find a two-output version of this card coded in R 😁.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2014 - 2015</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2014-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 22:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2014-2015/</guid>
      <description>Like the previous years, I continued with the tradition of sending a geek christmas card to my workmates.
This year I wrote it in R since it is one of the most used languages at my workplace, CREAL.
Winter card 2014 - 2015: snowflake recursion!
The result of running the script I sent (just a source code that loaded a file on the cloud) is seen above. The source code for that can be found at my christmas-card&amp;rsquo;s github (link) as mc201415.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2013 - 2014</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2013_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 22:14:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2013_2014/</guid>
      <description>This year I decided to continue with the tradition I started last year and sending a Christmas Card to my workmates written in python.
The result of running the script I sent is seen below.
Winter card 2013 - 2014: santa claus is coming to town
You can see the gallery of cards here and you have the source code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Card 2012 - 2013</title>
      <link>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2012-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 22:18:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://212.71.254.23/fun/winter_card_2012-2013/</guid>
      <description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to send a Christmas&amp;rsquo; card to my classmates. And since we are a bunch a little geeks, and I&amp;rsquo;m not an exception, here you have the postcard I sent them: A source-code-postcard in python.
The result of running the script is this:
Winter card 2012 - 2013: snowflake
You can see the gallery of cards here and you have the source code here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
